What if I told you the strategy
that most YouTubers are currently using
is going to
set them up for failure? In this video,
I'm going to help you understand why
abandoning my channel with over 450,000
subscribers was financially
the best decision I made this year,
and then the main trap
that you're going to
need to avoid if you're going to want to
grow your personal brand on YouTube in
2025.
When I think about the best who have ever
done it on YouTube, we must, of
course, credit MrBeast,
who put more thought and strategy into
ideation than anyone before.
When it comes to raising stakes in social
media,
there is no more aggressive strategy than
reinvestment and making videos just
wilder and crazier.
MrBeast turned retention into an art form
and continues to
dominate the landscape of YouTube.
Then personally,
one of my favorite content creators
is Matt Armstrong.
And Matt repairs crash-damaged cars,
and he doesn't just repair them,
he takes us
on winding story arcs intertwined with
retention editing.
And although I feel like his dad
is secretly the star of the show,
he's continued
his meteoric rise to be one of the biggest
YouTubers to emerge from the UK.
And he hasn't just provided entertainment,
he's inspired his audience.
Who knew that I was only two full GT3
builds away from getting one of them
myself?
And this kind of brings me onto another
point that I've spoken about in a lot of
other videos. There
is a certain amount of time
that someone's going to need to
spend in front of your videos before they
end up joining your program, buying your
services,
or generally just being impacted in the
way that you want from the
content. But what if I told you that
if you were to model your YouTube growth
off
those two creators,
or any creator similar to them,
that you'd be doing it
completely wrong? Well,
I'm going to explain exactly why that
is the case.
This is my Silver Play button.
I got it from another channel
that I created, and
just short of 500,000 subscribers,
I had to stop because I realized I
was making
the fundamental mistake I believe almost
95% of YouTubers are making right
now. And the mistake is this: I
was trying to be famous.
Now, you're probably thinking, "Why
is that a problem at all?" Well,
it's not if
you model your channel on making revenue
from Google via AdSense, but it's worth
noting that YouTube pays you pretty
terribly for the amount of effort, time,
and sacrifice necessary to make it in the
big leagues.
MrBeast has a huge amount of viewership
from younger generations who want to be
entertained.
Matt Armstrong has a massive viewership
from any bloke who wishes they
had a better car. That's a lot of people.
But in your situation, a bit like mine,
our cohorts are much smaller than we
realized.
I was making fitness-related content,
and it's difficult to get millions
of views to sustain yourself to make
videos on the leg press or how to squat.
Less than 20% of people in the UK even
have a gym membership, let alone use
YouTube as a place to watch fitness
content.
It's hard to make anything fitness-related
that interesting unless it's some kind
of wild challenge. And it
was only through creating content on my
old channel that
to make a video perform its best on
YouTube,
it had to move further away from the
reason I started the channel,
which in the beginning
was supposed to be to get me
more clients. But I had to sacrifice
that goal for more views, or I
was in a net
negative position for the end of each edit
for what I had to pay my videographer.
What became as a channel to get more PT
clients ended up as a machine to try
and go
viral every video,
with my biggest videos being about Whoop
or AG1 or the
downfall of modern podcasts,
or even having pops at Logan Paul.
And the caveat to this
is you can get sponsors.
MrBeast has Shopify,
Matt Armstrong has YFood and CarVertical.
I can also sense that Matt
is quite loyal to his early-day sponsors
because I
haven't seen an influx of new sponsorships
since the immense growth of his channel.
But for me, I don't do paid ads,
I don't do sponsorships.
I've never had a sponsor on any video
or anything that I've ever put out,
so using
monetization from that
was always going to be a problem.
Now, I know it can seem
that I suck off Matt a lot in my content,
but someone a
decade deep into content creation,
he's created something absolutely
fantastic, and
his execution is, quite frankly, flawless.
He's looked after people around him.
He stayed humble. He
is what every content creator should
aspire to be.
If most content creators could only take a
few lessons from Matt's journey, they'd
be doing themselves a favor.
But let's move on to another problem
that you're going
to face if you were going to try
and model Matt's growth for your own
channel.
Another problem arises
which can only be described as nurturing a
subpar audience.
We all know that in 2008, there
was a financial crisis.
Banks were bundling together subpar
mortgages and pretending they
were better than
they really were. Well,
growing a following for the sake of a
following is very
much the same. There
are a lot of big channels
and creators on platforms with
millions of followers who
are fucking broke.
There's tremendous pressure to stay afloat
with the views, and then all it takes is
for a single video to underperform,
and you're losing money month to month.
And all it takes is for the algorithm not
to favor your channel, and the stress and
the pressure is enough to push anyone to
the edge.
There's one thing your audience can sense,
and they won't like it, and that thing
is desperation. With Chris Williamson,
just over a year ago,
we launched Nootonic,
our own productivity drink,
and soon to be a fully-fledged nootropic
business.
Our launch,
although performing fantastically,
got quite a lot of heat, and the
criticism was almost exclusively from my
YouTube.
I realized soon after I launched
that I'd curated, yes, some
great audience,
but also a lot of subpar audience, an
audience that maybe I built trying to look
good, but as far as performance, if I
make videos about AG1 to get them in,
they're not true fans.
They're merely people
that maybe just enjoy seeing a business
getting taken down a
peg. So I started this channel,
a new channel with the sole objective of
getting
clients.
Ed Lawrence from the account Creator Booth
told me about a client that he
had who billed 33,000 US dollars from 800
views. Yeah, that's right.
Google would've probably paid him about $2
for that many
views.
But instead of relying on Google to pay
him, he paid himself.
Now, at the time of recording this video,
this channel has 19,000 subscribers, but
it's attributed towards 2 million US
dollars in my first year of business.
Rather than aiming to have the biggest
audience,
I just want a red-hot audience of
people who care about building their
business and their brand.
My biggest month trying to be famous on
the other YouTube channel was about 10,000
pounds for the month in AdSense.
My new business does 10 times that,
and I don't
even have monetization for this channel
turned on.
I made the mistake of trying to be famous
and trying to hack the algorithm for mass
views. But honestly,
you can run such a good business from just
catering to your
audience. When I look to 2025,
if I had to give one bit of advice,
it would be to
build a strong audience that
are likely to become customers,
not to try and build a
big audience full stop.
Where people do have massive channels,
they need sponsors,
and although they do get paid quite well,
they even have equity in certain brands.
They eventually start diluting their
personal brand because they become
semi-owned
by the sponsors. They can't say
or express certain things without
upsetting
those sponsors. I find it nice
that I don't have to answer to anyone,
and the fact
my monetization isn't even on means I
don't have to shit myself because I
accidentally said the word "fuck."
And we can all too easily set the wrong
metrics
for success on YouTube
and other social media platforms.
But take it from me,
you can't fly first class
or buy a nice car with likes from
your followers. You need clients.
You need business.
And the one thing I love more
and more than ever on this smaller
channel, I'm
curating an audience of personal brands,
small businesses, and people that
appreciate the hustle. They know the game.
They get it.
You and I know there
are going to be certain amount of times
that I'm going to need
to make a video that makes you go,
"Fuck me, I never thought of
that before." And
you'll consider buying my course
or one of my courses.
You won't even mind me saying, "Hey,
if you live in the UK or the USA,
buy a pack
of Nootonic,
you stingy cunt." I've fallen into the
trap of trying to be famous.
It pays well,
but it's a lot less exhausting just having
a red-hot audience of
people who are interested in you
and your business and your skills,
rather than
trying to jump on every flipping trend to
stay relevant and letting Google give you
a tiny little fraction of the cash
that you make them.
So remember,
when you're about to embark into a new
channel or a new social media
platform, think about this. What
is my business?
What problems do I solve?
Does this content align with both of
those?
Do not rely on AdSense as a strategy.
Although it works for some
and it works really well,
it fails the majority of
creators and leaves them stressing
and burning out desperately just trying to
get
clicks.
If you made it to the end of this video
and you think you have another one
in you, I'd recommend watching this one.
It could give you another, "Fuck me,
I never thought about it like that" kind
of
moment. Enjoy.